James McKeen Cattell Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: General Correspondence, 1884-1944 (Box 1-49)
  - Shattuck, George B., 1901-1905
  - Shufeldt, Robert W., 1902-1909
  - Shull, George H., 1907-1940
  - Skinker, C. F., 1934-1936
  - Smalley, Vincent R., 1939
  - Smith, David E., 1901-1909
  - Smith, Edgar F., 1898-1905
  - Smith, Edwin F., 1898-1910
  - Smith, Eugene A., 1897-1907
  - Smith, H. M., 1898-1908
  - Smith, Harlan I., 1899-1902
  - Smith, John B., 1900-1904
  - Smith, Louis H., 1901-1909
  - Smith, Theobald, 1900-1909 (Box 39)
  - Smith, W. G., 1894-1902
  - Soper, George A., 1901-1908
  - Soule, Malcolm H., 1938, 1944
  - Spalding, V. N., 1898-1905
  - Spaulding, Perley, 1907-1909
  - Spencer, J. W., 1902-1908
  - Spillman, W. J., 1902-1909
  - Spitzka, Edward A., 1901-1909
  - Stamm, G. W., 1940
  - Stanley, H. M., 1899-1901
  - Stannard, Edward D., 1924-1931
  - Starr, Frederick, 1900-1905
  - Starr, M. Allen, 1894-1908
  - Stearns, Robert E. C., 1900-1908
  - Sternberg, Charles H., 1902-1905
  - Sternberg, George M., 1899-1903
  - Stevens, W. LeConte, 1897-1909
  - Stevenson, John J., 1897-1909
  - Stewart, G. N., 1899-1907
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1899-1904
  - Stokes, H. N., 1902-1906
  - Stone, Whitmer, 1898-1907
  - Stratton, George M., 1897-1909
  - Strong, Charles A., 1897-1909
  - Sumner, F. B., 1902-1941
  - Super, Charles W., 1901-1909
  - Swain, George F., 1899-1909
  - Swift, Edgar J., 1900-1926
  - “Sab-Sma” miscellaneous (Box 40)
  - “Smi-Sze” miscellaneous (Box 41)
  - Thorndike, Edward L., 1900-1944 (Box 42)
  - Titchener, Edward B., 1884-1924
  - Tombo, Rudolf, Jr., 1902-1909
  - Trelease, Sam F., 1940-1942
  - Trelease, William, 1899-1926
  - “Tab-Thi” miscellaneous
  - “Tho-Tyr” miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - Udden, J. A., 1897-1909 (Box 44)
  - Underwood, L. M., 1898-1907
  - Underwood, William Lyman, 1902-1903
  - Upham, Warren, 1898-1906
  - “Und-Urb” miscellaneous
  - Van Amringe, J. H., 1899-1907
  - Van Hise, Charles R., 1898-1908
  - Van Wagnen, Theodore F., 1907-1909
  - Vaughan, T. Wayland, 1900-1939
  - Veblen, Oswald, 1904-1940
  - Verrell, A. E., 1897-1909
  - Very, Frank W., 1901-1903
  - Visher, Stephen S., 1936-1939
  - Von Struve, A. W., 1939-1941
  - “Vai-Vog” miscellaneous
  - Waddell, John, 1902-1908
  - Wadsworth, F. L. O., 1901-1903
  - Walcott, Charles D., 1899-1909
  - Waldo, Frank, 1894-1906
  - Walters, Raymond, 1909-1944
  - Ward, Henry B.
    - 1897-1934
    - 1935-1945 (Box 45)
  - Ward, Lester F., \, 1894-1908
  - Ward, Robert DeC., 1897-1909
  - Warren, Howard C., 1897-1929
  - Welch, William H., 1897-1907
  - Wenley, R. M., 1897-1924
  - Wheeler, W. M., 1899-1910
  - Whipple, George C., 1900-1905
  - Whipple, Guy M., 1901-1933
  - White, Charles A., 1900-1908 (Box 46)
  - Williams, Henry S., 1897-1904
  - Williams, J. G., 1925
  - Willis, Bailey, 1897-1910
  - Wilson, E. B., 1900-1944
  - Wilson, H. V., 1897-1907
  - Winchell, N. H., 1900-1909
  - Wissler, Clark, 1899-1908
  - Witmer, Lightner, 1896-1931
  - Wolff, Frank A., Jr., 1899-1902
  - Woodbridge, Frederick J. E., 1901-1909
  - Woodley, Sam, 1920-1942
  - Woodruff, Lorande Loss, 1907-1909
  - Woods, Albert F., 1899-1905
  - Woodward, R. S., 1897-1910
  - Woodworth, J. B., 1897-1907
  - Woodworth, R. S., 1899-1926
  - Woody, Thomas, 1934, 1939
  - Wright, Carroll D., 1899-1908 (Box 47)
  - Wyckoff, C. F., 1902
  - “Wad-Whi” miscellaneous
  - “Whi-Wor” miscellaneous (Box 48)
  - “Wra-Yud” miscellaneous (Box 49)
  - Zook, George F., 1934-1935
  - “Zam-Zyv” miscellaneous
  - Unidentified
- Part I: Family Correspondence, 1880-1944 (Box 50-57)
  *Containers no. 50-55 available on negative microfilm. Shelf no. 16,305, Reel nos. 1-3
  - 1880-Apr. 1885 (Box 50*)
  - May 1885-Apr. 1886 (Box 51*)
  - May 1886-Apr. 1887 (Box 52*)
  - May-Nov. 1887 (Box 53*)
  - Dec. 1887-Nov. 1888 (Box 54*)
  - Dec. 1888-Mar. 1903 (Box 55*)
  - Apr. 1903-Dec. 1906 (Box 56)
  - 1907-1944, undated (Box 57)
- Part I: Subject File (Box 58-69)
  Correspondence and near-print and typewritten copies of reports and bulletins.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Advertising (Box 58)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, (11 folders); (5 folders) (Box 59, Box 60)
  - American Men of Science, (7 folders); (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 61, Box 62, Box 63)
  - Psychological Corp., (7 folders) (Box 64, Box 65)
  - Science Press, (11 folders); (9 folders); (10 folders) (Box 66, Box 67, Box 68, Box 69)
- Part I: Speech, Article, and Book File, 1874-1946 (Box 70-74)
  Handwritten, typewritten, near-print, and printed copies of speeches and articles, and page proofs of the book James McKeen Cattell, 1860-1944; Man of Science.
  Grouped by type of material.
  - Bibliography (Box 70)
  - Speeches, 1933, undated
  - Articles
    - Holograph, 1874-1876, undated
    - Printed (Box 71)
      - 1885-1918
      - 1920-1946, undated (Box 72)
    - Proofs, (9 folders); (5 folders) (Box 73)
  - James McKeen Cattell, 1860-1944; Man of Science, page proofs (Box 74)
- Part I: Photographs (Box 75-76)
  Photographs of the Cattell family and others.
  Unarranged.
  - Family (Box 75)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 76)
- Part I: Miscellany (Box 77-86)
  Fragmentary notes, miscellaneous items, newspaper clippings, and memorabilia.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Account books (Box 77)
    - 1880-1932
    - 1937-1941, undated (Box 78)
  - Address books and passports
  - American Philosophical Society
  - Appointment books
  - Manuscript of Edward Drinker Cope's "Theological and Ethical Conclusions of Evolution"
  - Experimental notebooks (Box 79)
  - Notes fragments (Box 80)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks (Box 81)
  - Biographical material (Box 82)
  - Genealogy
  - Obituaries
  - Cattell family
  - General miscellany, (8 folders); (10 folders) (Box 83, Box 84, Box 85, Box 86)
- Part I: Printed Matter, 1869-1948 (Box 87-89)
  Pamphlets, chronologically arranged. Also magazine illustrations and newspaper clippings. Grouped by type of material.
  - Miscellany (Box 87)
  - Illustrations (Box 88)
  - Newspaper clippings, (13 folders) (Box 89)
- Part I: Certificates, Diplomas, Charts, Graphs, and Tables, 1880-1937 (Box 90)
  Oversize certificates, diplomas, and research material.
  - 1880-1937 (Box 90)
- Part II: Family Correspondence, 1835-1922 (Box 91-95)
  Letters exchanged between members of Cattell's family.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  *Containers no. 91-95 available on negative microfilm. Shelf no. 16,305, Reel nos. 4-7
  - Cattell, Alexander G. (Box 91*)
  - Cattell, Edward J.
  - Cattell, Eleth
  - Cattell, Elijah G.
  - Cattell, Elizabeth McKeen
  - Cattell, Elizabeth McKeen (Box 92*)
  - Cattell, Esther R.
  - Cattell, Henrietta Maillard
  - Cattell, Henry Ware
  - Cattell, Jaques
  - Cattell, Josephine Owen
  - Cattell, McKeen
  - Cattell, Psyche (Box 93*)
  - Cattell, Thomas W., Sr.
  - Cattell, Ware
  - Cattell, William C.
  - Cattell, William C. (Box 94*)
  - Cattell, William C. (Box 95*)
  - Ferriday, Harry M.
  - Ferriday, Helen
  - Ferriday, Lisa
  - Pittman, Josephine C.
  - Ware, Henry Burt
  - Ware, Sarah Cattell
  - Unidentified
- Part II: General Correspondence, 1880-1940 (Box 96-160)
  - Abbe, Cleveland (Box 96)
  - Abbot, Charles G.
  - Abbott, Alexander
  - Abbott, Ernest H.
  - Abel, John J.
  - Adams, Charles C.
  - Adams, Comfort A.
  - Adams, Eustace L.
  - Adams, Frank D.
  - Adams, Walter S.
  - Adler, Cyrus
  - Adler, Felix
  - Agassiz, Alexander
  - Agassiz, George R.
  - Agramonte, Aristides
  - Aitken, Robert G.
  - Albrecht, Sebastian
  - Alexander, Hartley B.
  - Alexander, Jerome
  - Aley, Robert Judson
  - Allen, Bennet M.
  - Allen, Glover M.
  - Allen, Harrison
  - Allen, Joel Asaph
  - Alsberg, Carl L.
  - Alvarez, Walter C.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - Ames, Joseph S.
  - Amstutz, Noah S.
  - Anderson, Edwin H.
  - Anderson, Rudolph M.
  - Andrews, Elisha B.
  - Andrews, Launcelot W.
  - Andrews, Roy Chapman
  - Angell, James Rowland
  - Angier, Roswell P.
  - Antevs, Ernst V.
  - Anthony, Harold E.
  - Arnold, Bion J.
  - Arnold, Ralph
  - Ashbrook, William A.
  - Ashley-Montagu, M. Francis
  - Atwater, Wilbur C.
  - Atwood, Wallace W.
  - Aydelotte, Frank
  - Ayres, Leonard P.
  - “Aa-Ad” miscellaneous
  - “Ag-Ar” miscellaneous (Box 97)
  - “As-Ay” miscellaneous (Box 98)
  - Bacon, Raymond F.
  - Baekeland, Leo H.
  - Baekeland, R. H.
  - Bagley, William C.
  - Bailey, Liberty H.
  - Bailey, Morton S.
  - Bailey, Pearce
  - Bailey, Solomon I.
  - Bailey, Vernon
  - Baker, Frank C.
  - Baker, Hugh
  - Baker, James H.
  - Baker, Marcus
  - Balch, Emily G.
  - Baldwin, J. Mark
  - Baldwin, Roger S.
  - Ball, Frank W.
  - Ballou, Frank W.
  - Bancroft, Wilder D.
  - Barbour, Clarence A.
  - Barbour, Thomas
  - Bardeen, Charles R.
  - Barker, Lewellys F.
  - Barnard, Edward E.
  - Barnes, Harry E.
  - Barrell, Joseph
  - Barrows, Albert L.
  - Bartlett, John H.
  - Barton, Bruce
  - Barton, Henry A.
  - Bartow, Edward
  - Bartsch, Paul
  - Barus, Carl
  - Bateson, William
  - Bauer, Louis A.
  - Baumgartner, William J.
  - Bawden, H. Heath
  - Beal, William J.
  - Beard, Charles A.
  - Beck, William H.
  - Becker, George F.
  - Bedell, Frederick (Box 99)
  - Beebe, William
  - Beer, George L.
  - Bell, Alexander Graham
  - Bell, Clark
  - Bender, Harold H.
  - Benedict, Francis G.
  - Bennett, Charles A.
  - Bennett, William M.
  - Benton, Guy Potter
  - Berger, G. C.
  - Bergey, David H.
  - Bergstrom, John A.
  - Berle, Adolph A.
  - Berry, Edward W.
  - Bess, Elmer Allen
  - Bessey, Charles E.
  - Biely, Jacob
  - Bigelow, Robert P.
  - Billings, John S.
  - Bingham, Hiram
  - Bingham, Millicent Todd
  - Bingham, Walter Van Dyke
  - Birdseye, Clarence
  - Birge, Edward A.
  - Birge, Raymond T.
  - Birkhoff, George D.
  - Bishop, William W.
  - Black, Davidson
  - Blackwelder, Eliot
  - Blakeslee, Albert F.
  - Blakeslee, George H.
  - Bloomfield, Maurice
  - Blumer, George
  - Boas, Franz
  - Bogert, Marston T.
  - Bolley, Henry L.
  - Bolton, Frederick E.
  - Boltwood, Bertram B.
  - Bonney, Thomas G.
  - Borah, William Edgar
  - Boring, Edwin Garrigues
  - Boss, Lewis (Box 100)
  - Bostwick, Arthur E.
  - Boutwell, William D.
  - Bowman, Isaiah
  - Bowman, John G.
  - Bragg, William H.
  - Brand, Charles
  - Brandeis, Louis D.
  - Bradshear, John A.
  - Bray, William L.
  - Breasted, Charles
  - Breasted, James H.
  - Breitwieser, J. V.
  - Brett, George P., Jr.
  - Bridges, Calvin B.
  - Bridgman, Percy W.
  - Briggs, Lyman J.
  - Brigham, Albert P.
  - Bright, James W.
  - Brill, Abraham A.
  - Brimhall, Dean R.
  - Britton, Nathaniel L.
  - Britton, S. W.
  - Brooks, Alfred H.
  - Brooks, Stratton D.
  - Brooks, William K.
  - Brown, Elmer E.
  - Brown, Ernest W.
  - Brown, F. C.
  - Brown, William Findley
  - Browne, Charles A.
  - Bruce, William S.
  - Brues, Charles T.
  - Brush, Charles F.
  - Brush, George J.
  - Bryan, William L.
  - Bucher, John E.
  - Buck, Solon J.
  - Buckner, Edward F.
  - Buisson, Ferdinand
  - Bumpus, Herman C.
  - Bunker, Frank F.
  - Burd, M. P.
  - Burg, John C.
  - Burgess, Albert F.
  - Burgess, Charles F.
  - Burgess, George K.
  - Burgess, John W.
  - Burleson, Arthur H.
  - Burr, William H.
  - Burton, Marion L.
  - Burton, Theodore E.
  - Bush, Vannevar
  - Bush, Wendell T.
  - Bush-Brown, Henry K.
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray
  - Butterfield, Ernest W. (Box 101)
  - Butterfield, Kenyon L.
  - “Bab-Bem” miscellaneous
  - “Ben-Boy” miscellaneous (Box 102)
  - “Bra-Bur” miscellaneous (Box 103)
  - “Bur-By” miscellaneous (Box 104)
  - Cady, Walter G.
  - Cajori, Florian
  - Caldwell, Otis W.
  - Calkins, Mary W.
  - Calvert, Philip P.
  - Campbell, Douglas H.
  - Campbell, William W.
  - Cannon, Walter B.
  - Cannon, William A.
  - Capen, Samuel Paul
  - Capps, Edward
  - Carhart, Henry S.
  - Carleton, Mark A.
  - Carlson, Anton J.
  - Carmichael, Leonard
  - Carnegie, Andrew
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
  - Carpenter, Ford A.
  - Carpenter, William H.
  - Carrel, Alexis
  - Carrington, Hereward
  - Carty, John J.
  - Carver, Thomas N.
  - Castle, William B.
  - Castle, William E.
  - Cathart, Henry S.
  - Cavanaugh, John
  - Century Association (Box 105)
  - Chamberlain, Charles J.
  - Chamberlain, Rollin Thomas
  - Chamberlain, Thomas C.
  - Chamberlain, W. A.
  - Chambers, Robert
  - Chambers, Will G.
  - Chandler, Charles F.
  - Chapman, Frank M.
  - Chapman, John Jay
  - Chase, Harry Woodburn
  - Chesnut, Victor K.
  - Cheyney, Edward P.
  - Child, Charles M.
  - Chittenden, Russell H.
  - Christian, Henry A.
  - Claparede, E.
  - Clark, Austin H.
  - Clark, George A.
  - Clark, George L.
  - Clark, Hubert L.
  - Clarke, Austin H.
  - Clarke, Frank W.
  - Clarke, John M.
  - Claxton, Philander P.
  - Clements, Frederic E.
  - Cleveland, Newcomb
  - Clute, Willard N.
  - Coblentz, William W.
  - Cockcroft, J. D.
  - Cockerell, Theodore D. A.
  - Cocks, R. S.
  - Coffman, Lotus D.
  - Cohen, Morris R.
  - Coker, Robert E.
  - Cole, Elbert C.
  - Collins, Frank S.
  - Compton, Arthur H.
  - Compton, Karl T.
  - Comstock, Ada Louise
  - Comstock, Anna Botsford
  - Comstock, George C.
  - Comstock, John Henry
  - Conant, James B.
  - Condon, Edward U.
  - Conklin, Edwin G.
  - Cook, Melville T.
  - Cook, Orator F.
  - Coolidge, Calvin
  - Coolidge, Harold J., Jr.
  - Coolidge, William D.
  - Cooper, Lane (Box 106)
  - Cooper, William J.
  - Copeland, Edwin B.
  - Copeland, Royal S.
  - Cottrell, Frederick G.
  - Coulter, John M.
  - Coulter, Stanley
  - Counts, George S.
  - Cowles, Henry C.
  - Cowley, W. H.
  - Crabtree, J. W.
  - Crafts, James M.
  - Craig, Charles F.
  - Craighead, Edwin
  - Crampton, Henry E.
  - Crane, Evan J.
  - Craven, Hermon W.
  - Creighton, James E.
  - Crew, Henry
  - Crile, George W.
  - Crocker, Francis B.
  - Crocker, William
  - Cross, Whitman
  - Crump, Clifford C.
  - Cummings, Bruce F.
  - Cunliffe, John W.
  - Curtis, George C.
  - Curtis, Harvey L.
  - Curtis, Heber D.
  - Curtis, John G.
  - Cushing, Harvey
  - Cushman, Allerton S.
  - Cutler, Elliott C.
  - “Cab-Cau” miscellaneous
  - “Ce-Cor” miscellaneous (Box 107)
  - “Cr-Cy” miscellaneous (Box 108)
  - Dabney, Charles W.
  - Dakin, Henry D.
  - Dale, Henry H.
  - Dall, William H.
  - Dallard, Charles
  - Daly, Reginald A.
  - Dana, Edward S.
  - Dana, John Cotton
  - Daniels, Arthur H.
  - Darling, Samuel T.
  - Darwin, Charles G.
  - Darwin, Horace
  - Davenport, Charles B.
  - Davenport, Eugene
  - Davis, Bradley M.
  - Davis, H. B.
  - Davis, Watson
  - Davis, William Harper (Box 109)
  - Davis, William M.
  - Davisson, Clinton J.
  - Dawes, Rufus
  - Day, Arthur L.
  - Day, Frank P.
  - Day, George Parmly
  - Dealey, James Q.
  - Dean, Bashford
  - Dearborn, George V. N.
  - Delabarre, E. B.
  - Dellenbaugh, Frederick S.
  - Denney, J. V.
  - De Vries, Hugo
  - Dewey, Davis R.
  - Dewey, John
  - Dewey, Melvil
  - Dickerson, Mary C.
  - Dickson, John
  - Dickson, Leonard E.
  - Diemer, Hugo
  - Dietz, David
  - Dixon, Roland B.
  - Dodd, William E.
  - Dodge, Cleveland E.
  - Dodge, Raymond
  - Dodge, Richard E.
  - Dodson, John M.
  - Dole, Charles F.
  - Dolley, Charles S.
  - Donworth, Albert B.
  - Doolittle, Charles L.
  - Doolittle, Eric
  - Dorsey, George A.
  - Douglas, Paul H.
  - Douglass, Andrew E.
  - Dowell, Philip
  - Drinker, Henry S.
  - Duane, Alexander
  - Duane, William
  - Du Bois, Eugene F.
  - Du Bois, W. E. Burghardt
  - Duggan, Stephen P.
  - Duggar, Benjamin M.
  - Duncan, George M.
  - Duncan, Robert K.
  - Dunn, Gano
  - Dunning, William A.
  - Durand, William F.
  - du Vigneaud, Vincent
  - Dyson, Frank W.
  - “Dav-Di” miscellaneous (Box 110)
  - “Do-Dy” miscellaneous (Box 111)
  - Earle, Ralph
  - East, Edward M.
  - Eastman, Charles A.
  - Eastman, George
  - Eastman, John R.
  - Eastman, Max F.
  - Eddington, Arthur S.
  - Edison, Thomas A.
  - Edman, Irwin
  - Edwards, Charles L.
  - Eglin, William C. L.
  - Eichelberger, William S.
  - Eigenmann, Carl H.
  - Eliot, Charles W.
  - Elliot, Daniel G.
  - Ellis, Havelock
  - Ellwood, Charles A.
  - Ely, Richard T.
  - Embree, Edwin R.
  - Emch, Arnold
  - Emerson, Charles F.
  - Ernst, Harold C.
  - Ettinger, William L.
  - Evans, Herbert McLean
  - Evermann, Barton W.
  - Ewing, James
  - "E" miscellaneous (Box 112)
  - Feckenthal, Frank D.
  - Fairchild, David G.
  - Fairchild, Henry P.
  - Fairchild, Herman L.
  - Fairlie, John A.
  - Falconer, Robert
  - Farley, James A.
  - Farlow, William G.
  - Farrand, Livingston
  - Farrand, Max
  - Farrington, Wallace R.
  - Faunce, William H. P.
  - Faust, Albert B.
  - Fay, Edward Allen
  - Feis, Herbert (Box 113)
  - Fermi, Enrico
  - Ferry, Frederick C.
  - Fessenden, Reginald A.
  - Fettermann, John C.
  - Fewkes, Jesse W.
  - Field, Richard M.
  - Fine, Henry B.
  - Finley, John H.
  - Fish, Carl Russell
  - Fish, Hamilton
  - Fish, Hamilton, Jr.
  - Fish, Stuyvesant
  - Fisher, Irving
  - Fisher, Sydney G.
  - Fisher, Walter K.
  - Fisher, Walter L.
  - Fiske, Thomas S.
  - Fleming, John A.
  - Fletcher, Alice C.
  - Fletcher, Horace
  - Fletcher, Robert
  - Flexner, Abraham
  - Flexner, Simon
  - Flint, Charles W.
  - Flint, Joseph M.
  - Flourney, Theodore
  - Flynn, John E.
  - Folkmar, Daniel
  - Folks, Homer
  - Forbes, Stephen A.
  - Ford, Alexander H.
  - Ford, Henry
  - Foster, William T.
  - Fowler, Harold N.
  - Fox, Philip
  - Frank, Glenn
  - Franklin, C. Ladd
  - Franklin, Edward C.
  - Franklin, Fabian
  - Franklin, William S.
  - Franz, Shepherd I.
  - Frost, Edwin B.
  - Fry, Henry J.
  - Fuertes, Louis Agassiz
  - Fullerton, George S.
  - Futrall, John C.
  - “Fao-Fo” miscellaneous (Box 114)
  - “Fr-Fu” miscellaneous (Box 115)
  - Gage, Simon H.
  - Gager, C. Stuart
  - Gale, Henry G.
  - Galton, Francis
  - Garfield, Harry Augustus
  - Garland, George M.
  - Garner, James W.
  - Garrett, Garet
  - Garrison, Fielding H.
  - Gasser, Herbert S.
  - Gay, Frederick P.
  - Gesell, Arnold
  - Gibbs, Wolcott
  - Gibney, Virgil P.
  - Giddings, Franklin H.
  - Guilder, Robert F.
  - Gildersleeve, Virginia C.
  - Gill, Theodore N.
  - Gilman, Benjamin I.
  - Glaser, Otto
  - Glynn, J. Martin
  - Goddard, Henry H.
  - Goddard, Pliny E.
  - Goddard, Robert H.
  - Godfrey, Hollis
  - Goldenweiser, Alexander
  - Goldschmidt, Richard
  - Gompers, Samuel
  - Gooch, Frank A.
  - Goodman, Nathan G.
  - Goodnow, Frank J.
  - Goodridge, Malcolm
  - Goodspeed, Arthur W.
  - Gordon, Neil E.
  - Gorgas, William C.
  - Gosling, Thomas W. (Box 116)
  - Gottheil, Richard
  - Grabau, Amadeus W.
  - Graham, Ben G.
  - Graham, Edward K.
  - Graham, Frank P.
  - Grattan, C. Hartley
  - Graves, Frank P.
  - Graves, Henry S.
  - Gray, John H.
  - Gray, William S.
  - Greely, Adolphus W.
  - Greene, Jerome D.
  - Greenman, Jesse M.
  - Greenman, Milton J.
  - Gregory, Richard
  - Gregory, William K.
  - Griffith, Ernest S.
  - Grinnell, Joseph
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert
  - Gudger, Eugene W.
  - Guerard, Albert Leon
  - Gulick, John T.
  - Gulick, Luther H.
  - Guyer, Michael F.
  - Gwinn, Joseph M.
  - “Ga-Gi” miscellaneous
  - “Go-Gu” miscellaneous (Box 117)
  - Haddon, Alfred C. (Box 118)
  - Hadley, Arthur T.
  - Hadow, William H.
  - Hagedorn, Hermann
  - Hagen, Johannes G.
  - Haggett, Arthur S.
  - Hague, Arnold
  - Haines, Thomas H.
  - Haldane, John S.
  - Hale, George E.
  - Hale, William B.
  - Hall, Asaph
  - Hall, Edward
  - Hall, Edwin H.
  - Hall, Frederic
  - Hall, G. Stanley
  - Hall, Ivan C.
  - Hall, Sidney B.
  - Hall, Winfield S.
  - Halsted, William S.
  - Hamilton, Alice
  - Hammer, William J.
  - Hammond, John Hays
  - Hamor, William Allen
  - Hardenbergh, Henry J.
  - Hargitt, Charles W.
  - Harkins, William D.
  - Harper, William R.
  - Harris, James Arthur
  - Harris, Rollin A.
  - Harrison, George R.
  - Harrison, Ross G.
  - Hart, Albert Bushnell
  - Hart, Edward
  - Hart, Hastings H.
  - Hart, Hornell
  - Hartwell, John A.
  - Harvey, E. Newton
  - Haskins, Caryl P.
  - Haskins, W. D.
  - Hausman, Leon A.
  - Hawkes, Herbert E.
  - Hay, Oliver P.
  - Hayes, Alfred, Jr.
  - Hayes, Carlton J. H.
  - Hayford, John F.
  - Hazard, F. S.
  - Heald, Frederick D.
  - Hecht, Selig
  - Hektoen, Ludvig
  - Heller, Otto
  - Henderson, Archibald
  - Henderson, Junius (Box 119)
  - Henderson, Lawrence J.
  - Henderson, Yandell
  - Henmon, Vivian A. C.
  - Henshaw, Samuel
  - Herrick, C. Judson
  - Herrick, Francis H.
  - Herring, Hubert
  - Herskovits, Melville J.
  - Herter, Christian A.
  - Herty, Charles H.
  - Hewitt, C. Gordon
  - Hewett, Edgar L.
  - Hibben, John G.
  - Hildebrand, Joel H.
  - Hill, Albert Ross
  - Hill, Archibald V.
  - Hill, David J.
  - Hillebrand, William F.
  - Hillquit, Morris
  - Hinsdale, Guy
  - Hirsch, Alcan
  - Hitchcock, Albert S.
  - Hitchcock, Charles H.
  - Hobbs, William H.
  - Hobhouse, Leonard T.
  - Hodge, Frederick W.
  - Hoffmeister, J. Edward
  - Holden, Edward S.
  - Holland, William J.
  - Hollick, Arthur
  - Hollick, Charles A.
  - Hollingworth, Harry L.
  - Hollister, Solomon C.
  - Holmes, Harry N.
  - Holmes, Henry W.
  - Holmes, John Haynes
  - Holmes, Joseph A.
  - Holmes, Samuel J.
  - Holmes, William H.
  - Holt, Hamilton
  - Holt, Henry
  - Holt, L. Emmett
  - Holt, Roland
  - Holzinger, Karl J.
  - Hooker, Davenport
  - Hooton, Earnest A. (Box 120)
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - Hopkins, Andrew D.
  - Hornaday, William T.
  - Hough, Theodore
  - Hough, Walter
  - Houser, Gilbert L.
  - Houston, David F.
  - Houston, Herbert S.
  - Hovey, E. O.
  - Howard, Leland O.
  - Howe, Harrison E.
  - Howe, Henry M.
  - Howe, James Lewis
  - Howe, Lucien
  - Howe, Marshall A.
  - Howell, William H.
  - Howison, George H.
  - Hrdlicka, Ales
  - Hubbard, Elbert G.
  - Huber, G. Carl
  - Hudson, Manley O.
  - Hudson, William H.
  - Huebner, Solomon S.
  - Huebsch, Benjamin W.
  - Hughes, Raymond M.
  - Hulburt, Lorrain S.
  - Hull, Cordell
  - Humphreys, W. J.
  - Hunt, Reid
  - Hunter, George W., III
  - Hunter, Walter S.
  - Huntington, Edward V.
  - Huntington, Ellsworth
  - Hutchins, Robert M. (Box 121)
  - Hutchins, William J.
  - Hutchisson, Elmer
  - Hyde, Arthur M.
  - Hyde, Edward P.
  - Hyde, Roscoe R.
  - Hylan, John J.
  - Hynek, Josef A.
  - Hyslop, James H.
  - “Haa-Harp” miscellaneous
  - “Harr-Hey” miscellaneous (Box 122)
  - “Hi-Hoy” miscellaneous (Box 123)
  - “Hub-Hy” miscellaneous (Box 124)
  - Ickes, Harold L.
  - Iddings, Joesph P.
  - Ingersoll, Ernest
  - Ingersoll, Leonard R.
  - Ingraham, Mark H.
  - Innes, Robert T.A.
  - Ives, Herbert E.
  - “I” miscellaneous
  - Jackson, A. V. Williams
  - Jackson, Clarence M.
  - Jackson, Dugald C.
  - Jacobs, Joseph
  - Jacoby, Harold
  - Jaggar, Thomas A.
  - James, Edmund J.
  - James, Henry, Jr.
  - James, William
  - Jameson, J. Franklin
  - Janet, Pierre M. F.
  - Janeway, Theodore
  - Jardine, William M.
  - Jastrow, Joseph
  - Jastrow, Joseph (Box 125)
  - Jeffrey, Edward C.
  - Jenks, Albert E.
  - Jenks, Jeremiah W.
  - Jennings, Herbert S.
  - Jennings, Walter L.
  - Jepson, Willis L.
  - Jessup, Walter A.
  - Jesup, Morris K.
  - Jewett, Frank B.
  - Johannsen, Oskar A.
  - Johnson, Allen
  - Johnson, Alvin
  - Johnson, Burges
  - Johnson, Douglas W.
  - Johnson, Duncan S.
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood
  - Johnston, Charles Hughes
  - Johnston, John
  - Johnston, John B.
  - Jones, E. Lester
  - Jones, Emmett Milton
  - Jones, Frederick S.
  - Jones, Lewis R.
  - Jordon, David Starr
  - Jordan, Edwin O.
  - Joslin, Elliott P.
  - Judd, Charles H.
  - Judson, Harry Pratt
  - Just, Ernest Everett
  - “Ja-Joh” miscellaneous
  - “Jol-Ju” miscellaneous (Box 126)
  - Kaempffert, Waldemar
  - Kandel, Isaac L.
  - Kapteyn, Jacobus C.
  - Karapetoff, Vladimir
  - Kasner, Edward
  - Kauffmann, Rudolph